# SAMIA SOUDAMINI SENZUTI

# Software Engineer | Web Developer | Cloud Solutions

- samiasoudamini@gmail.com
- 0410794849
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/samia-senzuti-599b19147/

- https://github.com/samiaSejuti
- https://samiasejuti.github.io/portfolio/
- Melbourne, VIC

#### SUMMARY

Passionate software engineer with experiences in web application development, data analysis, cloud technologies, Android IOS development and UI/UX design. A very creative, fast learner, and result-oriented: I try to do every work as perfect as possible.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Associate Instructor, Faculty of IT

#### MONASH UNIVERSITY

05/2023 - Present

Clayton, VIC

- Guide students in Front-End Web Development using the MVC design pattern
- Teach Bootstrap for UI/UX design, enabling students to create visually appealing and responsive websites.
- SQL database usage and management, preparing students for complex data handling.
- Teach deployment and management of web applications on Microsoft Azure cloud.

# **Industry Experience**

## MONASH UNIVERSITY & TELSTRA GROUP LTD.

07/2023 - 10/2023

Website: https://iteration3.univerze.me/

- Developed a platform with a five-member, diverse IT team to assist international students in settling in Melbourne
- Technologies Used: Next.js, React, Material-UI (MUI), DaisyUI, Tailwind CSS, MySQL, Vercel, Github

#### ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Associate Instructor, Data Fluency

## Monash University

06/2022 - Present

- Instruct Python and R programming for data exploration, cleaning, and interpretation, ensuring data readiness.
- Provide data visualization training using Python, R, MS Power BI, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript D3 library.
- Use R Shiny for the development of interactive web applications

# **Business Executive**

#### Business Automation Ltd.

11/2020 - 02/2021

 Managed IT products and streamlined help desk processes across 54 countries in the African region

# IT Business Analyst

# Apex Property Ltd.

09/2019 - 03/2020

- Developed and executed sales proposals while overseeing U.S. clients and contractors to ensure adherence to technical and business standards.
- Conducted onboarding sessions for new hires and developed training materials to enhance team skills.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Masters in Information Technology

Monash University

03/2021 - 12/2023

Clayton, VIC

## <u>SKILLS</u>

#### Front End Development

HTML CSS Javascript React Bootstrap Git

C# Next.js AWS Azure Rest API

#### Back End Development

SQL Mongodb PostgreSQL Firebase

Python Node.js Express.js

#### **PROJECTS**

NexaScan: Hospital CT scan scheduling platform

**Technologies Used**: C#, ASP.NET 7, Github, Bootstrap, MySQL

 The platform offers secure login, allowing patients to choose doctors, book visits, rate and review practitioners. It also enables administrators to send detailed reports and attachments to patients

# Containerized Image Detection and Serverless Cloud Storage

**Technologies Used**: Python, YOLOv3-tiny, OpenCV-Python, Flask, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS (Lambda, S3, API Gateway, DynamoDB, Cognito, IAM)

 A toll service that captures car number plates at gates, stores images in S3 bucket, uses Python to detect numbers, retrieves driver details from DynamoDB, and notifies drivers.

## Android goal setting app

**Technologies Used:** Java, Firebase, API, Mapbox

 Developed an Android app that allows users to authenticate, set goals, visualize their progress on maps, and track goal achievement.

#### **CERTIFICATION**

The Complete 2024 Web Development Bootcamp

#### **UDEMY**

Developed full-stack websites with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Bootstrap, React, and PostgreSQL.